<?xml version='1.0' encoding='windows-1252'?>
<GateDocument>
<!-- The document's features-->

<GateDocumentFeatures>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">gate.SourceURL</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">file:/E:/Users/conrada/Documents/My%20Dropbox/healthcare_data/training_3/hc075.txt</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">MimeType</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">text/plain</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">docNewLineType</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">CRLF</Value>
</Feature>
</GateDocumentFeatures>
<!-- The document content area with serialized nodes -->

<TextWithNodes><Node id="0" />Gingrich: <Node id="10" />1,968 Reasons to Repeal ObamaCare&#xd;<Node id="44" />
<Node id="45" />&#xd;
<Node id="47" />Posted by NN&amp;V Staff on Jan 19th, 2011 and filed under Government. You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0. Both comments and pings are currently closed.&#xd;
<Node id="225" />&#xd;
<Node id="227" />(Newt Gingrich) â&#x20ac;&#x201c; If you had any doubt about the importance of repealing the health reform law, <Node id="325" />a new chart from the Center for Health Transformation will give you 1,968 reasons to repeal the bill<Node id="425" />.&#xd;
<Node id="428" />&#xd;
<Node id="430" />The chart, titled â&#x20ac;&#x153;The New and Expanded Secretarial Powers in the Health Reform Lawâ&#x20ac;&#xfffd; reveals the ways in which <Node id="545" />the 2,700-page health reform law grants 1,968 powers to the Secretary of Health and Human Services<Node id="643" />.&#xd;
<Node id="646" />&#xd;
<Node id="648" />Control over the largest single sector of the American economy (about 18% of GDP, or one out of every five dollars in the entire economy) and a matter of life and death for every American, will be handed over to one appointed bureaucrat<Node id="884" />.&#xd;
<Node id="887" />&#xd;
<Node id="889" />Here are five outrageous examples the Center for Health Transformation found in the 1,968 grants of power:&#xd;
<Node id="997" />&#xd;
<Node id="999" />1. The Secretary determines â&#x20ac;&#x153;clinical concernâ&#x20ac;&#xfffd;of drugs â&#x20ac;&#x201d; Section 3307 â&#x20ac;&#x201d; (ii) IDENTIFICATION OF DRUGS IN CERTAIN CATEGORIES AND CLASSES. (I) â&#x20ac;¦ <Node id="1151" />the Secretary shall identify, as appropriate, categories and classes of drugs for which the Secretary determines are of clinical concern<Node id="1287" />. (II) CRITERIA. The Secretary shall use criteria established by the Secretary in making any determination under subclause (I). (iii) IMPLEMENTATION. The Secretary shall establish the criteria â&#x20ac;¦ and any exceptions â&#x20ac;¦ through the promulgation of a regulation which includes a public notice and comment period.&#xd;
<Node id="1600" />&#xd;
<Node id="1602" />Meaning: <Node id="1611" />The Secretary will decide what clinical drugs seniors can access<Node id="1675" />.&#xd;
<Node id="1678" />&#xd;
<Node id="1680" />2. Secretary decides how drugs are dispensed in long-term care facilities â&#x20ac;&#x201d; Section 3310 â&#x20ac;&#x201d; (3) REDUCING WASTEFUL DISPENSING OF OUTPATIENT PRESCRIPTION DRUGS IN LONG-TERM CARE FACILITIES. <Node id="1871" />The Secretary shall require PDP sponsors of prescription drug plans to utilize specific, uniform dispensing techniques, as determined by the Secretary<Node id="2021" />, in consultation with â&#x20ac;¦ any other stakeholders the Secretary determines appropriate â&#x20ac;¦ when dispensing covered part D drugs to enrollees who reside in a long-term care facility in order to reduce waste associated with 30-day fills.&#xd;
<Node id="2258" />&#xd;
<Node id="2260" />Meaning: <Node id="2269" />The Secretary will instruct physicians and nurses exactly how to give a drug to their patients in long-term care facilities<Node id="2392" />.&#xd;
<Node id="2395" />&#xd;
<Node id="2397" />3. â&#x20ac;&#x153;Tooth-level surveillanceâ&#x20ac;&#xfffd; â&#x20ac;&#x201d; Section 4102â&#x20ac;&#x201c; (2) NATIONAL HEALTH AND NUTRITION EXAMINATION SURVEY. The Secretary shall develop oral healthcare components that shall include tooth-level surveillance for inclusion in the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey â&#x20ac;¦ the term â&#x20ac;&#x2dc;tooth-level surveillanceâ&#x20ac;&#x2122; means a clinical examination where an examiner looks at each dental surface, on each tooth in the mouth and as defined by the Division of Oral Health of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.&#xd;
<Node id="2920" />&#xd;
<Node id="2922" />Meaning: <Node id="2931" />The Secretary will determine how dentists and dental hygienists should examine your teeth<Node id="3020" />.&#xd;
<Node id="3023" />&#xd;
<Node id="3025" />4. The Secretary may establish insurance premium ratings for states â&#x20ac;&#x201c; Section 1201 â&#x20ac;&#x201d; FAIR HEALTH INSURANCE PREMIUMS â&#x20ac;¦ SECRETARIAL REVIEW â&#x20ac;¦ With respect to the premium rate charged by a health insurance issuer for health insurance coverage offered in the individual or small group market â&#x20ac;¦ Each State shall establish 1 or more rating areas within that State for purposes of applying the requirements of this title. The Secretary shall review the rating areas established by each State under subparagraph (A) to ensure the adequacy of such areas for purposes of carrying out the requirements of this title. If the Secretary determines a Stateâ&#x20ac;&#x2122;s rating areas are not adequate, or that a State does not establish such areas, the Secretary may establish rating areas for that State.&#xd;
<Node id="3816" />&#xd;
<Node id="3818" />Meaning: <Node id="3827" />The Secretary can overrule states on what insurance rates can be whether they like it or not<Node id="3919" />.&#xd;
<Node id="3922" />&#xd;
<Node id="3924" />5. The Secretary may use comparative effectiveness research â&#x20ac;&#x201d; Section 6301(c) â&#x20ac;&#x201d; LIMITATIONS ON CERTAIN USES OF COMPARITIVE EFFECTIVENESS RESEARCHâ&#x20ac;¦ (2) Paragraph (1) shall not be construed as preventing the Secretary from using evidence or findings from such comparative clinical effectiveness research in determining coverage, reimbursement, or incentive programs under title XVIII based upon a comparison of the difference in the effectiveness of alternative treatments in extending an individualâ&#x20ac;&#x2122;s life due to the individualâ&#x20ac;&#x2122;s age, disability, or terminal illness.&#xd;
<Node id="4502" />&#xd;
<Node id="4504" />Meaning: The Secretary can use comparative effectiveness research to determine access to care for seniors, <Node id="4611" />like they do for patients in the British National Health Service<Node id="4675" />.&#xd;
<Node id="4678" />&#xd;
<Node id="4680" />Warnings about the Dictatorial Nature of Big Government&#xd;
<Node id="4737" />&#xd;
<Node id="4739" />This report confirms what I warned about in my book, To Save America: Stopping Obamaâ&#x20ac;&#x2122;s Secular Socialist Machine, which has just been released in an updated paperback, about how <Node id="4919" />the rush to socialism under the Obama administration puts all our freedoms at risk<Node id="5001" />.&#xd;
<Node id="5004" />&#xd;
<Node id="5006" />Of course, I am hardly the first to warn about the <Node id="5057" />inherently totalitarian nature of big government<Node id="5105" />:&#xd;
<Node id="5108" />&#xd;
<Node id="5110" />Thomas Jefferson warned in a letter to Charles Hammond that â&#x20ac;&#x153;When all government, domestic and foreign, in little as in great things, shall be drawn to Washington as the center of all power, it will render powerless the checks provided of one government on another and will become as venal and oppressive as the government from which we separated.â&#x20ac;&#xfffd;&#xd;
<Node id="5464" />&#xd;
<Node id="5466" />Freidrich Hayek warned in the Road to Serfdom that â&#x20ac;&#x153;<Node id="5520" />The more the state â&#x20ac;&#x2dc;plans,â&#x20ac;&#x2122; the more difficult planning becomes for the individual<Node id="5606" />.â&#x20ac;&#xfffd; Hayek also wrote in The Constitution of Liberty, â&#x20ac;&#x153;<Node id="5663" />Once wide coercive powers are given to governmental agencies for particular purposes, such powers cannot be effectively controlled by democratic assemblies<Node id="5818" />.â&#x20ac;&#xfffd;&#xd;
<Node id="5824" />&#xd;
<Node id="5826" />Even George Orwell, who was a left wing intellectual, understood <Node id="5891" />the danger of giving too much power to unelected bureaucrats<Node id="5951" />. Orwellâ&#x20ac;&#x2122;s novel, 1984, described dictatorship in London, not Moscow. He agreed with Hayekâ&#x20ac;&#x2122;s concerns in a review of the Road to Serfdom: â&#x20ac;&#x153;It cannot be said too oftenâ&#x20ac;¦collectivism is not inherently democratic, but, on the contrary, gives to a tyrannical minority such powers as the Spanish Inquisitors never dreamed of.â&#x20ac;&#xfffd;&#xd;
<Node id="6283" />&#xd;
<Node id="6285" />Dictatorial Powers Inspire Dictatorial Behavior:&#xd;
Kathleen Sebelius as a Case Study<Node id="6368" />&#xd;
<Node id="6370" />&#xd;
<Node id="6372" />These warnings about the corrupting nature of big government are already being shown to be true through the actions of Kathleen Sebelius, the current Secretary of the Health and Human Services<Node id="6564" />.&#xd;
<Node id="6567" />&#xd;
<Node id="6569" />Flushed with the promise of these 1,968 new grants of authority to her office, Secretary Sebelius recently made a series of threats to use one of these new powers to punish health insurance companies who have dared to tell the truth<Node id="6801" /> about how <Node id="6812" />the health reform law has led to rate hikes for their customers<Node id="6875" />.&#xd;
<Node id="6878" />&#xd;
<Node id="6880" />The idea of an unelected bureaucrat using her power to punish those who exercise their right to free speech should be considered abhorrent in a society that values liberty<Node id="7051" />.&#xd;
<Node id="7054" />&#xd;
<Node id="7056" />Also, as Karl Rove astutely pointed out in the Wall Street Journal , <Node id="7125" />Secretary Sebelius has also used her new powers to reward her friends<Node id="7194" />. <Node id="7196" />The Secretary has granted a number of companies exemptions from key requirements in Obamacare<Node id="7289" />. <Node id="7291" />More than a third of these companiesâ&#x20ac;&#x2122; employees are unionized compared to a mere 7% of the national workforce<Node id="7402" />.&#xd;
<Node id="7405" />&#xd;
<Node id="7407" />No Bureaucrat Should Have This Power<Node id="7443" />&#xd;
<Node id="7445" />&#xd;
<Node id="7447" />To be clear,<Node id="7459" /> the danger posed by Obamacareâ&#x20ac;&#x2122;s unprecedented centralization of power over our health decisions<Node id="7557" /> is bigger than the current occupant of the Secretary of HHS. <Node id="7619" />No unelected bureaucrat should have this amount of power<Node id="7675" />, whether he or she is in a Democratic or Republican administration.&#xd;
<Node id="7745" />&#xd;
<Node id="7747" />The genius of the founding fathers is that they understood the fallen nature of man and designed a system of government to prevent any one person from being so powerful that he or she could violate the rights of any citizen<Node id="7970" />.&#xd;
<Node id="7973" />&#xd;
<Node id="7975" />Every step we take toward bigger and bigger government throws this delicate balance off kilter<Node id="8069" />.&#xd;
<Node id="8072" />&#xd;
<Node id="8074" />As Milton Friedman warns, <Node id="8100" />giving power to bureaucrats to right the wrongs of society inevitably leads to worse results than that achieved by free people pursuing happiness on their own<Node id="8258" />. â&#x20ac;&#x153;<Node id="8263" />Where in the world do you find these angels,â&#x20ac;&#xfffd; Friedman asks â&#x20ac;&#x153;that are going to reorganize society for us?<Node id="8372" />â&#x20ac;&#xfffd;&#xd;
<Node id="8377" />&#xd;
<Node id="8379" />Considering the warning of Friedman and many more of historyâ&#x20ac;&#x2122;s great thinkers on liberty, <Node id="8471" />is it really any surprise that a political appointee would use new, unprecedented powers to reward friends and punish opponents?<Node id="8599" />&#xd;
<Node id="8601" />&#xd;
<Node id="8603" />The very fact that the Secretary is now so powerful that she can unilaterally punish opponents of the new healthcare law shows how dangerous this bill is to the freedom of the American people<Node id="8794" />.&#xd;
<Node id="8797" />&#xd;
<Node id="8799" />And this new study rom the Center for Health Transformation shows that <Node id="8870" />there are 1,968 reasons why all Americans who value liberty should insist their elected representatives support full repeal of the healthcare law<Node id="9015" />. <Node id="9017" /></TextWithNodes>
<!-- The default annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet>
<Annotation Id="68" Type="arg" StartNode="6285" EndNode="6368">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">threatens_freedom</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="69" Type="arg" StartNode="7407" EndNode="7443">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">govt_reaching_beyond_authority</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="64" Type="arg" StartNode="8100" EndNode="8258">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">expands_govt</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="65" Type="rel" StartNode="8263" EndNode="8372">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">expands_govt</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="66" Type="arg" StartNode="8471" EndNode="8599">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">politicizes_healthcare_system</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="67" Type="arg" StartNode="8603" EndNode="8794">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">threatens_freedom</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="35" Type="doc" StartNode="0" EndNode="9017">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">id</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">hc076</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">author</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String"></Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">source</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">nevada,news,views</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">date</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">20110119</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">side</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">anti</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">url</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://nevadanewsandviews.com/archives/7901</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="38" Type="rel" StartNode="545" EndNode="643">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">bill_should_be_defunded/not_passed</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="39" Type="arg" StartNode="648" EndNode="884">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">centralizes_healthcare_control</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="36" Type="arg" StartNode="10" EndNode="44">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">bill_should_be_defunded/not_passed</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">positive</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="37" Type="arg" StartNode="325" EndNode="425">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">bill_should_be_defunded/not_passed</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">positive</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="42" Type="arg" StartNode="2931" EndNode="3020">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">increases_govt_interference_in_healthcare_decisions</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="43" Type="arg" StartNode="3827" EndNode="3919">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">centralizes_healthcare_control</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="40" Type="arg" StartNode="1611" EndNode="1675">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">restricts_healthcare_choice</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="41" Type="arg" StartNode="2269" EndNode="2392">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">increases_govt_interference_in_healthcare_decisions</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="46" Type="arg" StartNode="6372" EndNode="6564">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">expands_govt</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="47" Type="arg" StartNode="6569" EndNode="6801">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">attacks_on_insurance_companies_are_politically_motivated</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="44" Type="rel" StartNode="4611" EndNode="4675">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">similar_programs_have_failed_abroad</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">incomplete</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="45" Type="arg" StartNode="4919" EndNode="5001">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">expands_govt</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="51" Type="rel" StartNode="7291" EndNode="7402">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">bill_is_politically_motivated</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="50" Type="rel" StartNode="7196" EndNode="7289">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">bill_is_politically_motivated</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String"></Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="49" Type="arg" StartNode="7125" EndNode="7194">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">bill_is_politically_motivated</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="48" Type="arg" StartNode="6812" EndNode="6875">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">individuals_will_pay_more</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="55" Type="arg" StartNode="5057" EndNode="5105">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">govt_reaching_beyond_authority</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">incomplete</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="54" Type="rel" StartNode="1871" EndNode="2021">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">increases_govt_interference_in_healthcare_decisions</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="53" Type="rel" StartNode="1151" EndNode="1287">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">restricts_healthcare_choice</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="52" Type="arg" StartNode="8870" EndNode="9015">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">bill_should_be_defunded/not_passed</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">positive</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="59" Type="arg" StartNode="6880" EndNode="7051">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">govt_reaching_beyond_authority</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">incomplete</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="58" Type="arg" StartNode="5891" EndNode="5951">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">govt_reaching_beyond_authority</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">incomplete</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="57" Type="arg" StartNode="5663" EndNode="5818">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">govt_reaching_beyond_authority</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="56" Type="arg" StartNode="5520" EndNode="5606">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">increases_govt_interference_in_healthcare_decisions</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="63" Type="rel" StartNode="7975" EndNode="8069">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">expands_govt</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="62" Type="rel" StartNode="7747" EndNode="7970">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">govt_reaching_beyond_authority</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="61" Type="arg" StartNode="7619" EndNode="7675">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">govt_reaching_beyond_authority</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">incomplete</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">true</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="60" Type="arg" StartNode="7459" EndNode="7557">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ss-label</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">centralizes_healthcare_control</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">unclear</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String"></Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">type</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">label</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">polarity</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">negative</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

<!-- Named annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet Name="Original markups">
<Annotation Id="0" Type="paragraph" StartNode="0" EndNode="45">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="1" Type="paragraph" StartNode="47" EndNode="225">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="2" Type="paragraph" StartNode="227" EndNode="428">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="3" Type="paragraph" StartNode="430" EndNode="646">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="4" Type="paragraph" StartNode="648" EndNode="887">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="5" Type="paragraph" StartNode="889" EndNode="997">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="6" Type="paragraph" StartNode="999" EndNode="1600">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="7" Type="paragraph" StartNode="1602" EndNode="1678">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="8" Type="paragraph" StartNode="1680" EndNode="2258">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="9" Type="paragraph" StartNode="2260" EndNode="2395">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="10" Type="paragraph" StartNode="2397" EndNode="2920">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="11" Type="paragraph" StartNode="2922" EndNode="3023">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="12" Type="paragraph" StartNode="3025" EndNode="3816">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="13" Type="paragraph" StartNode="3818" EndNode="3922">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="14" Type="paragraph" StartNode="3924" EndNode="4502">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="15" Type="paragraph" StartNode="4504" EndNode="4678">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="17" Type="paragraph" StartNode="4739" EndNode="5004">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="16" Type="paragraph" StartNode="4680" EndNode="4737">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="19" Type="paragraph" StartNode="5110" EndNode="5464">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="18" Type="paragraph" StartNode="5006" EndNode="5108">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="21" Type="paragraph" StartNode="5826" EndNode="6283">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="20" Type="paragraph" StartNode="5466" EndNode="5824">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="23" Type="paragraph" StartNode="6372" EndNode="6567">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="22" Type="paragraph" StartNode="6285" EndNode="6370">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="25" Type="paragraph" StartNode="6880" EndNode="7054">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="24" Type="paragraph" StartNode="6569" EndNode="6878">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="27" Type="paragraph" StartNode="7407" EndNode="7445">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="26" Type="paragraph" StartNode="7056" EndNode="7405">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="29" Type="paragraph" StartNode="7747" EndNode="7973">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="28" Type="paragraph" StartNode="7447" EndNode="7745">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="31" Type="paragraph" StartNode="8074" EndNode="8377">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="30" Type="paragraph" StartNode="7975" EndNode="8072">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="34" Type="paragraph" StartNode="8799" EndNode="9017">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="32" Type="paragraph" StartNode="8379" EndNode="8601">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="33" Type="paragraph" StartNode="8603" EndNode="8797">
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

</GateDocument>
